A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, Issue Books, Series 17 FA363
Rockefeller Archive Center
- First Gubernatorial Term, 1958-1962; 2; 5.4 Cubic Feet
  - Volume 26 - Rehabilitation, 1958-1962 (Box 33, Folder 186)
    Tab 14 NAR Statement -- address by Governor Rockefeller to Governor's Committee on Employing the Physically Handicapped, New York City, October 9, 1959.
    Tab 15 NAR Statement -- address by Governor Rockefeller to Governor's Council on Rehabilitation, Albany, October 29, 1959.
    Tab 16 Report -- First Report of Governor's Council on Rehabilitation, December 21, 1959.
    Tab 17 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 6, 1960.
    Tab 18 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Governor Rockefeller's Special Message to the Legislature, on operation of a rehabilitation field laboratory, March 7, 1960.
    Tab 19 Legislation -- Executive Order establishing an Interdepartmental Health and Hospital Council, March 31, 1960.
    Tab 20 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller that New York led all States in persons rehabilitated during Fiscal 1959-1960, August 2, 1960.
    Tab 21 NAR Statement -- Proclamation, Employ the Physically Handicapped Week, September 19, 1960.
    Tab 22 Report -- Report on Organization Study of State Rehabilitation Services, October 1960.
    Tab 23 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller and Report, on new Pilot Rehabilitation Center in Syracuse, October 17, 1960.
    Tab 24 Report -- Report by New York State Governor's Council on Rehabilitation, December 19, 1960.
    Tab 26 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of a pilot comprehensive rehabilitation center at the proposed State University Teaching Hospital of the Upstate Medical Center at Syracuse, April 13, 1961.
    Tab 27 Report -- Interim Report of and statement of Governor's Council on Rehabilitation, July 3, 1961.
    Tab 28 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of Youth Rehabilitation centers in the State, November 15, 1961.
    Tab 29 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message by Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 3, 1962.
    Tab 30 NAR Statement -- address by Governor Rockefeller at annual meeting of Governor's Committee on "Employ the Physically Handicapped," on New York's accomplishments in rehabilitation, New York City, March 16, 1962.
    Tab 31 NAR Statement -- statement on program to expand rehabilitation services for the handicapped (Annual Report of Governor's Council on Rehabilitation), April 2, 1962.
    Tab 32 NAR Statement -- Address by Governor Rockefeller at meeting of Region II of the "National Rehabilitation Association," on New York's rehabilitation program, New York City, May 16, 1962.
    Tab 33 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of State assistance for the care of children born deformed as result of drugs, August 3, 1962.
  - Volume 27 - Social Insurance, 1958-1962 (Box 33, Folder 187)
    Tab 1 Summary and Background on Social Insurance in New York State -- prepared for NAR Special New York Project (Perkins-Kieffer), June 18, 1962.
    Tab 2 NAR Campaign Statement -- Policy Statement by NAR on Rehabilitation of Physically Disabled Persons, September 28, 1958.
    Tab 3 NAR Campaign Statement -- Policy Statement by NAR on Labor, October 3, 1958.
    Tab 4 NAR Campaign Statement -- excerpts from remarks by NAR before a dinner sponsored by Schenectady County Republican Committee, Van Curler Hotel, October 13, 1958.
    Tab 5 NAR Campaign Statement -- remarks by NAR on a telecast, WABC-TV, October 27, 1958.
    Tab 7 NAR Statement -- statement on funds appropriated in State Budget, for aging, the blind, the disabled, and dependent children, February 15, 1959.
    Tab 8 Legislation -- An Act, To amend the workmen's compensation law, in relation to coverage of employers of one or more employees, February 18, 1959.
    Tab 9 Legislation -- An Act, To amend the labor law, in regularization of employment under the unemployment insurance law, March 12, 1959.
    Tab 10 Legislation -- An Act, To provide for temporary emergency unemployment benefits, March 18, 1959.
    Tab 11 Legislation -- An Act, To amend the labor law, in relation to terms of coverage under the unemployment insurance law, March 18, 1959.
    Tab 12 Legislation -- An Act, To amend the workmen's compensation law, in relation to providing for the payment of claims against uninsured defaulting employers; and establishing and prescribing for the maintenance of an uninsured employer's fund, March 19, 1959.
    Tab 13 Press Release, March 24, 1959 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Int. 1797, Pr. 1807, permitting members of State Retirement System to withdraw therefrom, March 24, 1959.
    Tab 14 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1959 -- Chapters 419, 229, 313, 314, 311, 578, 502, 312.
    Tab 15 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, March 23, 1959.
    Tab 16 Transcript - text of statewide telecast by NAR over WCBS-TV, April 15, 1959.
    Tab 17 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller on appointment of Intergovernmental Committee to study scope of investments of pension funds for employees of the State and political subdivisions, August 16, 1959.
    Tab 18 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller supporting Amendment #7, authorizing increased pensions to retired policemen, firemen, and dependents, November 1, 1959.
    Tab 19 Summary of Special Study on Investment of Pension Funds -- (Leg. Research Rept.), November 11, 1959.
    Tab 20 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 6, 1960.
  - Volume 27 - Social Insurance, 1958-1962 (Box 33, Folder 188)
    Tab 21 NAR Statement -- Announcement by Governor Rockefeller of 7% Take-Home Pay Increase for State employees, February 24, 1960.
    Tab 22 Report -- report of Governor's Committee on the Investment of Public Pension Funds, March 3, 1960.
    Tab 23 Report -- report of Governor's Committee on the Vesting of Pension Rights, March 9, 1960.
    Tab 24 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of legislation to supplement pensions of State and local employees and teachers, March 11, 1960.
    Tab 25 Press Release, May 1, 1960 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Int. 2400, Pr. 2423, increasing maximum limits on medical services under Workmens Compensation, without prior authorization, April 30, 1960.
    Tab 26 Press Release, May 1, 1960 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Int. 3873, Pr. 4574, granting preferential supplemental pensions to State retired teachers, April 30, 1960.
    Tab 27 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1960 -- Chapters 783, 787, 792, 789, 781, 790, 791, 265.
    Tab 28 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller and Legislative leaders to support legislation extending deadline for supplemental pensions under old act, May 28, 1960.
    Tab 29 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 4, 1961.
    Tab 30 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller, proposing an extension of unemployment insurance benefits for additional 13 weeks, February 1, 1961.
    Tab 31 Press Release, April 15, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 3325, Pr. 3609, as creating a dangerous precedent in excluding, non-profit cemetery corporations from unemployment insurance, April 11, 1961.
    Tab 32 Press Release, April 23, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 3053, Pr. 3296, authorizing local school districts to grant "increased-take-home-pay" to teachers who are members of State Teachers' Retirement System, April 18, 1961.
    Tab 33 Press Release, April 24, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 1962, Pr. 5142, providing that any disability or death to firemen or policemen, "while in the line of duty, resulting from heart injury, shall be presumed an accident," April 22, 1961.
    Tab 34 Press Release, April 25, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 2148, Pr. 4177, increasing from 1/2 to 3/4 of final salary the death benefit of the State Employee's Retirement System, April 22, 1961.
    Tab 35 Press Release, April 25, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 585, Pr. 5222, increasing the compensation authorized to retired members of State Teachers' Retirement System, April 24, 1961.
    Tab 36 Press Release, April 25, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 2230, Pr. 5340, authorizing fire districts to permit maximum benefits under the Workmen's Compensation Law, April 24, 1961.
    Tab 37 Press Release, April 25, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 542, Pr. 542, authorizing municipalities to provide "minimum" monthly benefits of $120 to retired policemen and widows, April 24, 1961.
    Tab 38 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments: Chapters 194, 38, 233, 119, 440, 431, 419, 853, 336, 906, 321, 302, 557, 230, 826, 920, 965.
    Tab 39 NAR Statement -- excerpts from interview of Governor Rockefeller by Gannett News Service Correspondents, on unemployment insurance benefits, Albany, June 1, 1961.
    Tab 40 NAR Statement -- excerpt from address by Governor Rockefeller to Union Label and Service Trades Council of Greater New York and Long Island AFL-CIO, on New York progressive program on social legislation, September 24, 1961.
    Tab 41 NAR Statement -- address by Governor Rockefeller to Convention of New York State AFL-CIO, on administration accomplishments in workmen's compensation and disability benefits, October 23, 1961.
    Tab 42 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 3, 1962.
    Tab 43 NAR Statement -- excerpts from television appearance of Governor Rockefeller on WNEW-TV, on reasons for increased social insurance and minimum wage, New York City, April 9, 1962.
    Tab 44 Press Release, April 14, 1962 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 1098, Pr. 1101, providing that any disability or death to a fireman or policeman in the line of duty shall be presumed an accident, April 9, 1962.
    Tab 45 Press Release, April 20, 1962 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 3623, Pr. 3744, prohibiting forfeiture of unemployment insurance benefits for errors in claimants application unless proven wilfully false beyond a reasonable doubt, April 18, 1962.
    Tab 46 Press Release, April 29, 1962 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 2907, Pr. 3103, increasing the accidental death benefit for member of the State Employees' Retirement System, April 24, 1962.
    Tab 47 Press Release, May 1, 1962 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 1011, Pr. 4344, providing increased supplemental pensions for teachers, April 29, 1962.
    Tab 48 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1962 -- Chapters 55, 276, 456, 422, 999, 218, 249, 169, 255, 404, 233, 291, 1004, 886, 175, 114, 675, 676, 746, 569, 648, 570, 801, 95, 491.
  - Volume 28 - State Administration Organization, 1958-1962 (Box 33, Folder 189)
    Tab 1 Fact Sheet -- "Public Employees," prepared by Republican Legislative Research Staff, 1958.
    Tab 2 NAR Campaign Statement -- excerpts from remarks by NAR, at dinner sponsored by Delaware, Greene and Ulster County Republican Committees, Kingston, October 16, 1958.
    Tab 3 NAR Campaign Statement -- excerpt from statement by NAR on campaign proposals, October 19, 1958.
    Tab 4 NAR Campaign Statement -- excerpts of remarks by NAR at Queens County Republican Committee Rally, Elmhurst, October 29, 1958.
    Tab 5 NAR Campaign Statement -- excerpts of remarks by NAR before the Civil Service Employees Association, Albany, October 13, 1958.
    Tab 6 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor-elect Rockefeller on proposed inventory of the work of all executive departments and agencies, December 26, 1958.
    Tab 7 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller on survey of Executive branch of State Government, January 4, 1959.
    Tab 9 NAR Statement -- Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature on Civil Defense, March 25, 1959.
    Tab 10 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1959 -- Chapters 335, 204, 212, 836, 569, 200, 4, 343; Senate Pr. 1010, Assembly Pr. 1623.
    Tab 11 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller on appointment of 12 members to State Defense Council, June 15, 1959.
    Tab 12 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller on first meeting of reorganized State Defense council, July 4, 1959.
    Tab 13 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller and Republican Legislative Leaders, on economy of State Government, September 16, 1959.
    Tab 14 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller supporting Amendment #1 to create a State Department of Motor Vehicles, November 1, 1959.
    Tab 15 Summary of Special Studies on Efficiency and Organization of Executive Branch -- (Leg. Research Rept.), November 11, 1959.
    Tab 16 Report -- report of Committee on Reorganization of Executive Branch, December 28, 1959.
    Tab 17 NAR Statement -- Pre-Session Special Message to the Legislature on Reorganization of the Executive Branch, December 29, 1959.
    Tab 19 NAR Statement -- excerpts from Address by Governor Rockefeller to New York State Women's Joint Legislative Forum on reorganization, January 12, 1960.
  - Volume 28 - State Administration Organization, 1958-1962 (Box 33, Folder 190)
    Tab 20 NAR Statement -- excerpts from Annual Budget Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, February 1, 1960.
    Tab 21 NAR Statement -- statewide telecast by Governor Rockefeller and Lieutenant Governor, on Reorganization of State Government, March 29, 1960.
    Tab 22 Report -- report by Commissioner of Motor Vehicles on reorganization of Bureau of Motor Vehicles, April 25, 1960.
    Tab 23 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1960 -- A. Int. 4343, Pr. 4567; Chapters 459, 460, 461, 462, 463, 320, 321, 335, 330, 323, 322, 329, 325, 324, 464, 465, 331, 341, 233, 326.
    Tab 24 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of a Management Institute, June 20-22, for improvement of state services, May 27, 1960.
    Tab 25 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of selection of 30 State employees for a year's special training in public administration, June 7, 1960.
    Tab 26 Legislation -- Executive Order by Governor Rockefeller, on combining activities of various State agencies on sanitation inspections of restaurants, July 11, 1960.
    Tab 27 Legislation -- statement and Executive Order by Governor Rockefeller establishing Code of Fair Practices for Executive Department, July 15, 1960.
    Tab 28 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of Comparative Study of Salaries in State Government and Outside Employment, November 6, 1960.
    Tab 29 NAR Statement -- joint statement by Governor Rockefeller and Comptroller on establishment of Accounting Improvement Committee, December 22, 1960.
    Tab 30 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 4, 1961.
    Tab 31 Report -- Analyzing The Compensation of New York State Employees, January 26, 1961.
    Tab 32 Correspondence -- letter from Mayor Wagner to Governor Rockefeller charging corruption in State government, January 31, 1961.
    Tab 33 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller, on not tolerating misconduct or corruption in State Government and answering Mayor Wagner's charges, February 3, 1961.
    Tab 34 NAR Statement -- excerpt from address by Governor Rockefeller to Association of Towns of State of New York, on establishment of new Executive Office of Urban and Regional Development, February 7, 1961.
    Tab 35 NAR Statement -- excerpt from interview of Governor Rockefeller on CBS NEWS, on proposed increase in State salaries, March 1, 1961.
    Tab 36 NAR Statement -- Announcement by Governor Rockefeller of Salary Program to make state salaries competitive with private industry, March 2, 1961.
    Tab 37 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1961 -- Chapter 202, Senate Bill Int. 501, Chapters 219, 416, 398, 197, 18, 482, 613, 614, 615, 946, Senate Resolution 101, Chapters 472-476.
    Tab 38 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of proposed $3.5 million State Office Building in Buffalo, April 27, 1961.
    Tab 39 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller that State Crime Commission is bipartisan and Mayor's charge is without foundation, April 27, 1961.
    Tab 40 NAR Statement -- excerpts from interview between Governor Rockefeller and Gannett News Service Correspondents, on progress towards State's reorganization, Albany, May 23, 1961.
    Tab 41 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller that Division of Budget will sponsor an Executive Institute on Electronic Data Processing, June 17, 1961.
    Tab 42 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of appointment of representatives of the construction industry to serve on new State Building Code Council, June 19, 1961.
    Tab 43 Pamphlet -- "The Government of the State of New York," June 30, 1961.
    Tab 44 NAR Statement -- announcement of program to facilitate transfer and promotion of State's employees by reimbursement of travel expenses, July 3, 1961.
    Tab 45 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller that 4,000 State laborers are now on annual salary basis and receive added benefits, July 10, 1961.
    Tab 46 NAR Statement -- excerpt from address by Governor Rockefeller to The American Legion, on program of State's Division of Veterans' Affairs, Albany, July 27, 1961.
    Tab 47 NAR Statement -- announcement of new building at Campus Site for Department of Taxation and Finance, September 22, 1961.
    Tab 48 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of Temporary State Commission on the Celebration of the Centennial of the Morrill Land-Grant Act, September 22, 1961.
    Tab 49 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1962 -- Chapter 592.
  - Volume 29 - State and Local Relations (New York City), 1958-1962 (Box 34, Folder 191)
    Tab 1 Background Paper -- State-Local Relations in New York State, Milton Alpert, n.d.
    Tab 2 Fact Sheet -- Local Assistance, prepared by Republican Legislative Research Staff, 1958.
    Tab 3 Fact Sheet -- entitled State Aid to New York City, prepared by Republican Legislative Research Staff, 1958.
    Tab 4 NAR Campaign Statement -- speech by NAR at Republican Family Jamboree, Syracuse, September 8, 1958.
    Tab 5 NAR Campaign Statement -- address by NAR at meeting of the County Officers Association of the State of New York, Grossinger's September 30, 1958.
    Tab 6 NAR Campaign Statement -- excerpt from statement by NAR on campaign proposals, October 19, 1958.
    Tab 7 NAR Campaign Statement -- excerpts from remarks by NAR at Bronx County Republican Committee Rally, Bronx, October 31, 1958.
    Tab 9 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller and Legislative Leaders on new taxing powers requested by Mayor of New York City, March 16, 1959.
    Tab 10 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller on city and state relationships, April 9, 1959.
    Tab 11 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1959 -- Chapters 368, 369-371, 532, 857-862, Assembly Pr. 52.
    Tab 12 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller on appointment of Temporary State Commission on Governmental Opportunities of New York City, May 6, 1959.
    Tab 13 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller supporting Amendment #4 permitting New York CIty to issue additional $500 million in bonds for schools, November 1, 1959.
    Tab 14 Summary of Special Study on New York City (Leg. Research Rept.), November 11, 1959.
    Tab 15 NAR Statement -- statement on progress of Temporary State Commission on New York City Operations, November 11, 1959.
  - Volume 29 - State and Local Relations (New York City), 1958-1962 (Box 34, Folder 192)
    Tab 17 Report -- Interim Report of Temporary State Commission on New York City Operations, February 1, 1960.
    Tab 18 NAR Statement -- statement on estimated State-aid to localities for 1959-1960 and 1960-1961, February 9, 1960.
    Tab 19 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller on setting record straight on New York City-State fiscal relations, February 12, 1960.
    Tab 20 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller congratulating Mayor Wagner on decision to revise City Charter, February 16, 1960.
    Tab 21 NAR Statement -- joint statement by Governor Rockefeller and Mayor Wagner, on New York City problems, March 17, 1960.
    Tab 22 Press Release, March 22, 1960 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Int. 52, Pr. 2971, imposing substantial cost on New York City for medical services for retired teachers, March 22, 1960.
    Tab 23 NAR Statement -- joint statement by Governor Rockefeller and Mayor Wagner on New York State-New York City fiscal relations, March 26, 1960.
    Tab 24 NAR Statement -- joint statement by Governor Rockefeller and Legislative Leaders on New York State-New York City fiscal relations, March 26, 1960.
    Tab 25 Press Release, April 30, 1960 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Int. 1503, Pr. 4349, authorizing supplemental pensions for retired New York City teachers, April 29, 1960.
    Tab 26 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1960 -- Chapters: 1032, 1033, 1034, 1960-1961 Executive Budget; Chapter 418.
    Tab 27 NAR Statement -- directive by Governor Rockefeller on transferring the investigatory work of the Commission Governmental Operations of the City of New York to the Commission of Investigation, May 5, 1960.
    Tab 28 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller and Comptroller of revised schedule of State aid for New York city, July 10, 1960.
    Tab 29 Report -- Interim Report on New York City General Business and Financial Tax, December 1960.
  - Volume 30 - State and Local Relations (New York City), 1958-1962 (Box 34, Folder 193)
    Tab 31 NAR Statement -- statement concerning unbiased investigation of New York City by Commission of Investigation, January 24, 1961.
    Tab 32 Correspondence -- letter from Governor Rockefeller to Mayor Wagner, requesting information of corruption in State government, January 28, 1961.
    Tab 33 Correspondence -- letter from Governor Rockefeller to Mayor Wagner, concerning increased State-aid for New York City, January 31, 1961.
    Tab 34 Correspondence -- letter from Mayor Wagner to Governor Rockefeller, charging corruption State government, January 31, 1961.
    Tab 35 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor Rockefeller, answering Mayor Wagner's charges of corruption in State government, February 3, 1961.
    Tab 36 Correspondence -- letter from Governor Rockefeller to Mayor Wagner, agreeing that procedures be established for voters to express views on new charter, February 7, 1961.
    Tab 37 NAR Statement -- statement by Governor's Press Secretary, answering Mayor Wagner's charge that New York City would lose state aid for education, March 1, 1961.
    Tab 38 NAR Statement -- announcement by Governor Rockefeller of introduction of bill to permit Mayor Wagner to appoint a Charter Revision Commission, March 4, 1961.
    Tab 39 Press Release, April 25, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 173, Pr. 1288, permitting members of the New York City Police Pension Fund to change their election of a retirement plan, April 24, 1961.
    Tab 40 Press Release, April 25, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 2243, Pr. 2365, extending the deadline for the transfer of members between certain New York City retirement systems, April 24, 1961.